Guide to the Nationality Rooms Program Office Files, Second Deposit, 1927-2012 UA.40.01a
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Nationality Rooms Program Office Files, Second Deposit
1927-2012
1970-2012
ULS Archives & Special Collections
University of Pittsburgh. Nationality Rooms Program
Mitchell, Ruth Crawford
UA.40.01a
12.92 Linear Feet (11 boxes)
These records represent the second deposit of office files created and collected by the Nationality Rooms Program.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Deposited by the Nationality Rooms Program Office in December 2014.
Custodial History
The collection was housed in the Nationality Rooms Office until it was processed from October 2014 to January 2015. It was transferred to the University Archives after processing.
Arrangement
The collection comprises the following series:
Series I. Office Files
Series II. Scholarships
Series III. Events
Series IV. Publicity
History
The University of Pittsburgh's Nationality Rooms Program was developed by Chancellor Dr. John G. Bowman and Ruth Crawford Mitchell to engage the citizens in the Pittsburgh region. Following the completion of the Cathedral of Learning in 1926, Bowman and Mitchell aimed for unique classrooms that reflect the ethnic heritage of the people who settled Western Pennsylvania. As the rooms were being planned and constructed, there was a need to oversee these activities and to develop the policies under which they were to operate. After their rooms were built, the committees focused on raising funds for scholarships for University of Pittsburgh students. The Summer Study Abroad scholarships sponsored by the Nationality Rooms Committees reflect decades of work by those committees to honor an ideal--education through cultural exchange.
The Nationality Rooms Program Office continues to administer and oversee the scholarships, oversee the construction of new rooms and the ongoing maintenance of existing rooms.
Previous Citation
Nationality Rooms Program Office Files, Second Deposit, 1927-2012, UA.40.01a, University Archives, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Scope and Content Notes
This is a collection of office files from the Nationality Rooms Program. Included are reports, policies, correspondence, related organizations, newsletters, and other materials relating to the day to day operation of the office. It also includes the documents that are created by the administration of the Study Abroad Scholarships.
Related Material
Nationality Rooms Program Office Files, Initial Deposit, UA.40.01, 1926-1966, University Archives, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Universities and colleges -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Ethnic groups -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Classrooms -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; University of Pittsburgh; Bowman, John G. (John Gabbert); Tsui, John H.; Bruhns, E. Maxine; Slater, Vilma; Mitchell, Ruth Crawford; Slater, Frank; Nationality Rooms (Cathedral of Learning, Pittsburgh, Pa.); Skewis, Savina S.; University of Pittsburgh. Nationality Rooms Program; Rush, Helen Pool; University of Pittsburgh. Nationality Rooms Program; Prostrednik, Stanley; University of Pittsburgh; McGunagle, Mary Ann; McGunagle, George F.; Manasterski, Eugene; Bruhns, Fred C.; Blatt, Genevieve; Heinz, Vira I.; Hunt, Rachel McMasters Miller; Knox, James W., 1919-2001; Lawrence, David Leo; Cathedral of Learning (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
- Office Files, 1927-2012; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  This is a collection of office files from the Nationality Rooms Program. Included are reports, policies, correspondence, related organizations, newsletters, and other materials relating to the day to day operation of the office.
  - Reports, 1927-2009; 1.
    Staff meetings, annual reports, financial reports, and projections of the rooms from 1927 until the G-20 Summit in 2009. Documents in this subseries also include the University of Pittsburgh's history and description of each individual Nationality Room.
    - Staff Meeting Minutes, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Staff Meeting Minutes, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Staff Meeting Minutes, 1975-1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Staff Meeting Minutes, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Staff Meeting Minutes, 1978-1980 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Annual Reports, 1970-1980 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Annual Reports, 1971-1977 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Complete Cost of Finished Nationality Rooms, 1927-1954 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Rooms Cost Projections, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Program Ideas, 1955-1965 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Tour Statistics, 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Nationality Rooms Descriptions, Post-1995 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Room Descriptions, Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Brief Descriptions, Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - University of Pittsburgh History, 1945-1976 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - History Notes, Undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Union Election, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Old World American, 1940s (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Miscellaneous Reports, 1946-1971 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Miscellaneous Reports, 1958-1970 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Report to Chancellor, 1946-1971 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - P.I.P. Info Area – Room & V.C. Settlement, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Responsibilities of NRIEP, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Nationality Rooms Sixtieth Anniversary, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - PA Heritage Affairs Commission, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Grant PHMC Commission, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - G-20, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Policies and Procedures, 1960-2001; 2.
    A collection of the policies and procedures implemented in the Nationality Rooms throughout the years that enabled the program to flourish. Sample policies and procedures include: fundraising, deed of gift procedure, and the architectural guidelines for the rooms.
    - Policies for the Nationality Rooms, 1974-2001 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Policies for the Nationality Rooms, 1966-1996 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - University Policies, 1990-1993 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Procedures, 1938-1988 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Standing Rules and Function of RMS, 1977-1982 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Fundraising Ideas and Procedures, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Deed of Gift Procedure and Samples, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Architect Guidelines, 1983-1999 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Alumni Giving, 1976-1979 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Budget, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Outdated Information, Circa 1960-1975 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence, 1938-2012; 3.
    This subseries has the different types of correspondence throughout the Nationality Rooms' office and committees. The types of correspondence include: use of the room, inquiries, new room inquiries, complaints, and in-office memos to name a few.
    - Nationality Council Correspondence, 1938-1954 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Nationality Council Correspondence, 1949-1954 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Card from the Polish Room, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Use of the Nationality Rooms, 1994-2000 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Nationality Council, 1991, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - New Room Inquiries, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - New Room Inquiries, 1976-1980 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - New Rooms, 1972-1980 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Bulgarian Room, 1976, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Nationality Rooms Program, 1972-1975 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Nationality Rooms Program, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Nationality Rooms Program, 1971-1976 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Nationality Rooms Program, 1966-1985 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Memos on Committees, 1954-1963 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Memos on Committees, 1955-1957 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Chinese Historical Society of America, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Courthouse Gallery/Forum, 1978-1980 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Van Dusen Memos, 1972-1981 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Complaints, 1974-1991 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Complaints, 1992-2011 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Complaints, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Public Relations, 1977-1981 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Frank A. Zabrosky, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Obituaries, 1962-1974 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Obituaries, 1974-1983 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Obituaries, 1962-2012 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Sympathy, 1973-1983 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Testimonials, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Inter-Office Memos, 1971-1979 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Inter-Office Memos, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Inter-Office Memos, 1966-1968 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Staff Memos, 1986-1998 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Miller, Donald, 1972-2004 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Pitt Informal Program, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Office of Urban and Community Services, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - Physical Plant, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - References, 1969-1980 (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - Foreign Festival Customs, Undated (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - American Association of Museums, 1986-1988 (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - PA Federation of Museums and Historical Organizations, 1998-2011 (Box 2, Folder 78)
    - Pittsburgh Foundation, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 79)
    - Museum Grant, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 80)
    - Postcards with Script, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 81)
    - Pathfinders, 2007-2009 (Box 2, Folder 82)
    - Mongolian Higher Education Project, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Facility Management, 1962-2011; 4.
    This subseries contains the documents pertaining to the physical maintenance and management of the facilities. This includes the individual Nationality Rooms and the Cathedral of Learning in general.
    - Annual Maintenance Tour, 2008-2010 (Box 2, Folder 84)
    - Annual Maintenance Tour, 2004-2008 (Box 2, Folder 85)
    - Annual Maintenance Tour, 2003-2005 (Box 2, Folder 86)
    - Floor Care, 1975-1986 (Box 2, Folder 87)
    - Exterior Soot Removal, 2007-2010 (Box 2, Folder 88)
    - Commons Room Custodial Requests, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 89)
    - Cathedral of Learning Custodial Requests, 2007-2011 (Box 2, Folder 90)
    - Smoking Policies, 1967-1996 (Box 2, Folder 91-92)
    - Vandalism and Bomb Threats, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 93)
    - Nationality Rooms Thefts, 1962-1977 (Box 2, Folder 94)
    - Security Reports, 1962-1985 (Box 2, Folder 95)
    - Space, 1974-1980 (Box 2, Folder 96-97)
    - Space Management/Accounting & Analysis, 1984-1997 (Box 2, Folder 98)
    - Furniture, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 99)
    - Furniture Loans, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 100)
    - Facilities Management, 1994-2008 (Box 3, Folder 101)
    - Elevator and Third Floor Access, 1987-1994 (Box 3, Folder 102)
    - Electronic Upgrades, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 103)
    - Lighting Maintenance, 1994-2006 (Box 3, Folder 104)
    - Lighting Maintenance, 1997-1999 (Box 3, Folder 105)
    - Chinese Lighting Fixtures, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 106)
    - Markers for Classrooms, 2004-2007 (Box 3, Folder 107-111)
    - Historic Marker, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 112)
    - Room Signs, 1986-2009 (Box 3, Folder 113)
  - Complementary Facilities, 1951-2009; 5.
    A subseries of documents in regards to facilities which are administered by the Nationality Rooms Program.
    - 1209 Cathedral of Learning, 1980-1984 (Box 3, Folder 114)
    - 1228 Cathedral of Learning History, 1992-1998 (Box 3, Folder 115)
    - 1228 Cathedral of Learning History, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 116)
    - 1228 Cathedral of Learning History, 1983-1992 (Box 3, Folder 117)
    - 12th Floor Cathedral of Learning History and Policies, 1951-2009 (Box 3, Folder 118)
    - 12th Floor Cathedral of Learning History and Policies, 2004-2005 (Box 3, Folder 119)
    - Information Center, 1969-1971 (Box 3, Folder 120)
    - Visitor's Center, 1972-1975 (Box 3, Folder 121-122)
    - Visitor's Center, 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 123)
    - Visitor Information Center, 1978-1982 (Box 3, Folder 124)
    - Garden Proposal and Memos, 1993-2003 (Box 3, Folder 125)
    - Nationality Rooms Garden, 1993-1998 (Box 3, Folder 126)
    - Gift Center Remodeling Project, 2003-2011 (Box 3, Folder 127-130)
  - Facilities with Historical Significance within the University, 1966-2011; 6.
    This subseries focuses on the facilities that are not officially affiliated with the Nationality Rooms Program, but are administrated by the University of Pittsburgh.
    - Heinz Memorial Chapel, 1991-2001 (Box 4, Folder 131-132)
    - Heinz Memorial Chapel, 1972-1991 (Box 4, Folder 133)
    - Stephen Foster, 1966-1985 (Box 4, Folder 134-136)
    - Stephen Foster Date Requests, 1990-1996 (Box 4, Folder 137)
    - Stephen Foster New Policy, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 138)
    - Log Cabin, 1987-2000 (Box 4, Folder 139)
    - P.I.P. Downtown Info. Center, 1980-1981 (Box 4, Folder 140)
    - Frick Fine Arts, 1991-2010 (Box 4, Folder 141)
  - Similar Organizations, 1973-1995; 7.
    This subseries looks at the other programs similar to the University of Pittsburgh's Nationality Rooms. Focus is placed upon Cleveland Ethnic Rooms, Wayne State University, sister-city Scheffield, and Nationality Rooms elsewhere in the 1990's.
    - Cleveland Ethnic Rooms, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 142)
    - Wayne State University, 1973-1982 (Box 4, Folder 143)
    - Sister City Sheffield, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 144)
    - Nationality Rooms Efforts Elsewhere, 1993, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 145)
  - Newsletters, 1990-2003; 8.
    A collection of the newsletters sent out by the Nationality Rooms Office regarding the rooms. Topics range from Room history, scholarships, publicity, and events.
    - 1990-1993 (Box 4, Folder 146)
    - 1993-1997 (Box 4, Folder 147)
    - 1997-2000 (Box 4, Folder 148)
    - 2001-2003 (Box 4, Folder 149)
  - Websites, 2003-2006; 9.
    This subseries is a collection that focuses on the websites created by the Nationality Rooms Office or the Rooms individually. Documents include memos, printed screenshots, and emails.
    - Website, 2003-2006 (Box 4, Folder 150)
  - Architectural Drawings, 1940-1998; 10.
    This subseries has some of the architectural drawings and sketches for the Nationality Rooms as well as other rooms under the direction of the Nationality Rooms Office.
    - 3rd Floor Floor Plans, 1989-1994 (Box 4, Folder 151)
    - 3rd Floor Floor Plans, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 152)
    - 12th Floor Floor Plans, 1993, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 153)
    - Nationality Rooms Floor Plans, 1947-1948 (Box 4, Folder 154)
    - 1st Floor Floor Plans, Circa 1970s (Box 4, Folder 155)
    - 1st Floor Floor Plans, Circa 1940s-1970s (Box 4, Folder 156)
    - Facility Floor Plans and Policies, 1980-1988 (Box 4, Folder 157)
    - Japanese Room Architectural Drawings, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 158)
    - Armenian Room Architectural Drawings, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 159)
    - Oversized Drawings 1
      Contains architectural drawings and sketches for the following rooms: Croghan-Schenley, Welsh, Romanian, Hungarian, Scottish, Yugoslav, Swedish, Chinese, Czechoslovak, Norwegian, Polish, Italian, English, French, German, Russian, Syria-Lebanon and Armenian Rooms. Also several drawings for room 124 Cathedral (Executive Offices).
    - Oversized Drawings 2 (Box 6)
      Contains architectural drawings and sketches for the Ukranian and Armenian Classrooms and 3 copies of the Bowman Calligraphy.
  - Other files, 1995-2002; 11.
    A collection of files with topics that were of interests to the Director.
    - Max Vanka Murals, 1995-1997 (Box 4, Folder 160)
- Scholarship Files, 1957-2012; II.
  A collection of the scholarships given out by the Nationality Rooms and Intercultural Exchange Program throughout the years. Reports by students who received the scholarships and who the scholarships are in honor of is also within this collection. This series also contains photographic materials.
  - Scholarship Reports and Evaluations, 1957-2010; 1.
    This subseries focuses on the reports given by the scholarship winners, Nationality Rooms and Intercultural Exchange Program. Correspondence, progress reports, finished reports, and photographic materials make up the bulk of this collection.
    - Summer Study Abroad Prgogram Survey, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 161)
    - Summer Study Abroad Prgogram Survey, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 162)
    - Summer Study Abroad Prgogram Survey, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 163)
    - Organization for the Foreign Visitor and Student in Pittsburgh, Pa., U.S.A, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 164)
    - Helen Pool Rush Grant – Rachel E. Kloock, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 165)
    - Africa Room Nationality Scholarship Award – Rebecca Stroup (Rwanguba), 2002 (Box 5, Folder 166)
    - Nationality Rooms Committee and Women's International Club – Heather H. Kiraly, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 167)
    - Amy Erica Smith, 2007 (Box 5, Folder 168)
    - Keith Williams (Uraguay), 1996 (Box 5, Folder 169)
    - Dan Bisbee (Scotland), 2010 (Box 5, Folder 170)
    - Sera W. Kariuki (Kenya), 1997 (Box 5, Folder 171)
    - Eugene Manasterski Memorial Ukrainian Room Research Grant – Kumen R. Call, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 172)
    - Oksana Doroshkevich (Ukraine), 2003 (Box 5, Folder 173)
    - Abigail Chua, Medical Research in Philippines Poster, 2008 (Box 5, Folder 174)
    - Ruth Crawford Mitchell Memorial Award – Adrienne R. Washington (Caribbean nations), 2008 (Box 5, Folder 175)
    - Center for Latin American Studies Field Trip – Monica Faust (Brazil), 2001 (Box 5, Folder 176)
    - Rachel Kloock (Mexico), 1999 (Box 5, Folder 177)
    - Miscellaneous Items, 1967-1980 (Box 5, Folder 178)
    - Charles Elliot Scholarship Mate, 1957-1958 (Box 5, Folder 179)
    - Elanore K. Shenesky – Fred Schaefer Memorial Scholarship, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 180)
    - Carolyn J.P. Shaw – Stanton C. Crawford Scholarship, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 181)
    - John S. Ruskay – "S" Award, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 182)
    - Beverly Reifman – Frederic Schaefer Memorial Scholarship, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 183)
    - Susan E. Scott – French Committee Scholarship 1965, 1965-1969 (Box 5, Folder 184)
    - Gladys Flesher – Vira Heinz Award 1957, 1957-1958 (Box 5, Folder 185)
    - Richard A. Moore – Italian Award, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 186)
    - Maye Rattner – Student Hostess Award, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 187)
    - Louis Sprajcar – Norwegian Award, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 188)
    - Marcia H. Getting – Vira Heinz Award, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 189)
    - Joseph J. Fitzharris – EMITT Award, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 190)
    - Esther J. Mishelevich – French Award, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 191)
    - Award Program – General, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 192)
    - 1958 Final Reports, 1957-1958 (Box 5, Folder 193)
    - Student Award Program, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 194)
    - Study Abroad Evaluation, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 195)
  - Scholarship Information, 1969-2012; 2.
    A collection regarding the scholarships given out by the Nationality Rooms and the Office of Cultural Education Exchange. This collection also focuses on those whose names are honored by the scholarships. News clippings, photographic materials, published materials for publicity, correspondence, and obituaries of those involved are the types of documents that make up the bulk of this collection.
    - Kosciuszko Foundation, 1969-1982 (Box 5, Folder 196)
    - Sir William Radcliffe Award and Biography Information, 1969-1983 (Box 5, Folder 197)
    - James W. Knox, 1977-1982 (Box 5, Folder 198)
    - James Knox Scholarship Fund, 1995-2003 (Box 5, Folder 199)
    - Tsui Endowment – New York Contact, 1978-1986 (Box 5, Folder 200)
    - John Tsui, 1982-2010 (Box 5, Folder 201)
    - Rosemund Fund, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 202)
    - Prostrednik, 1977-1981 (Box 5, Folder 203)
    - Savina S. Skewis – Memorial Service, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 204)
    - Savina S. Skewis Endowment, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 205)
    - Savina S. Skewis - General, 1965-1993 (Box 5, Folder 206)
    - Helen Pool Rush, 1965-2007 (Box 5, Folder 207)
    - Vira I. Heinz, 1983-2005 (Box 5, Folder 208)
    - Ivan Santa-Cruz, 1994-2003 (Box 6, Folder 209)
    - David L. Lawrence Award, 1981-2010 (Box 6, Folder 210)
    - Ruth Crawford Mitchell, 1975-2011 (Box 6, Folder 211)
    - Ruth Crawford Mitchell Scholarship Fund, 1991-2007 (Box 6, Folder 212)
    - Ruth Crawford Mitchell Scholarship Fund, 1980-1990 (Box 6, Folder 213)
    - Education Exchange Endowment Fund, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 214)
    - Endowments, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 215)
    - Caryl M. Kline, 2002-2009 (Box 6, Folder 216)
    - Caryl M. Kline Scholarship, 2002-2006 (Box 6, Folder 217)
    - John Heinz Scholarship Endowment Fund, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 218)
    - E. Maxine Bruhns Scholarship, 2005-2008 (Box 6, Folder 219)
    - Shiono Scholarship, 2009-2011 (Box 6, Folder 220)
    - McGunagle Award, 2007-2012 (Box 6, Folder 221)
    - Italian, 1986-1992 (Box 6, Folder 222)
    - Slater, Frank and Vilma, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 223)
    - Blatt Endowment, 1996-1997 (Box 6, Folder 224)
    - Brown, Dorothy Bradley, 1998-2007 (Box 6, Folder 225)
    - Brown P.T. Award, 1998-2008 (Box 6, Folder 226)
    - Starrett, Charles and Agnes, 1982-1989 (Box 6, Folder 227)
    - Kessler, Friedl, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 228)
    - Rachel McMasters Miller Hunt Scholarship, 1979-2008 (Box 6, Folder 229)
    - Stadnick, Mary, 1993-1995 (Box 6, Folder 230)
    - Scholarship – Publicity, 1998-2007 (Box 6, Folder 231)
    - Rukavina, Miles (Mr. and Mrs.), 1980-1983 (Box 6, Folder 232)
    - Dravo, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 233)
- Events, 1942-2012; III.
  This series contains documents, photographs, and other materials that reflect the various events that took place at, or were related to, the Nationality Rooms. Types of events include: a Christmas and Holiday Open House, Nationality Room dedications, foreign ambassador visits, the celebration of the United States of America's Bicentennial, and more.
  - Bicentennial of the United States of America, 1974-1983; 1.
    This subseries documents the city of Pittsburgh's celebration of the Bicentennial of the United States of America. Included are correspondence and meeting minutes regarding the celebrations, as well as a history of the Cathedral of Learning.
    - Bicentennial Committee, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 234)
    - Presentation of History of Cathedral of Learning Given by E.M. Bruhns, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 235)
    - Pittsburgh Bicentennial Events, 1975-1981 (Box 6, Folder 236-237)
    - Tourism Advisory Board Meetings, 1974-1975 (Box 6, Folder 238)
  - VIP Visitors, 1973-1982; 2.
    This subseries is devoted to the various visitors that the University of Pittsburgh has welcomed, most of which toured the Nationality Rooms during their stay. VIPs include ambassadors from Greece, the United Nations, and Norway; the Swedish Consul; Polish Head of State; and Lord Mayor of Sheffield.
    - VIPs, 1974-1982 (Box 6, Folder 239)
    - Food Editors Visit, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 240)
    - Cameroon Visitor, African Heritage Classroom Committee, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 241)
    - American Debate Team, Russian Room, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 242)
    - Lord Mayor of Sheffield, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 243)
    - American Society of Interior Designers Tour, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 244)
    - Greek Ambassador John A. Tzounis, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 245)
    - American Orff-Schulwerk Association, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 246)
    - Mayor of Lucca, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 247)
    - Scottish Room VIPs, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 248)
    - Mayor's Conference, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 249)
    - People's Republic of China, Minister of Metallurgic Industries, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 250)
    - Japanese Room, Osaka Chamber Of Commerce, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 251)
    - Russian VIPs, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 252)
    - Swedish Consul General, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 253)
    - United Nations Ambassadors Visit Correspondence, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 254)
    - United Nations Ambassadors Visit Publicity, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 255)
    - Norwegian Ambassador, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 256)
    - Visit of Polish Head of State, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 257)
    - U.S. Steel Christmas Choral Festival, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 258)
    - French Ambassador Morot-Sir Visit, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 259)
  - Anniversaries, 1966-2012; 3.